hey professor dave let's check out the
night sky
[Music]
it's taken almost 10 billion years but
we finally made it we started with a big
bang
we watched adam's form
we saw these collect forms stars and
galaxies we saw those stars explode to
disperse the materials that would become
all the planets and we watched our own
solar system form including the planet
earth thus begins a new chapter of the
story
upon this earth biomolecules arose
polymerized and became contained in cell
membranes life was born which slowly
evolved and eventually brought about
human beings like you and me this
fascinating chapter of the story is told
by the field of general chemistry
organic chemistry biochemistry and
biology check out my tutorials on those
subjects if you want to know more about
that whole show since it's more than a
little involved as one might
imagine i just thought it'd be fun to
have a little persona professor dave
it's just a little name um you know i
don't know
anything but i you know did uh work in
um you know i took courses without
components uh in as an undergrad and
then i did most of the masters in
synthetic but i didn't really last long
i dropped out of my semester
again for music opportunities and i
eventually got this teaching job uh for
organic chemistry at this little trade
university it was pretty great because
the bachelor's degree i was supposed to
teach the laboratory portion but on the
first day the lecture instructor had
this freakout we just took
[Music]
you're not enjoying chemistry but
through a bunch of bureaucracy quite
frankly i lost that job withdrawal yet
again from from the master program a lot
of you asked very infectiously are you a
real professor i sit literally in this
room uh like 60 to 70 hours a week and
uh i chose the name really without much
thought uh it was kind of telling you to
be honest right um i just thought it'd
be fun to have a little personal
professor it's just a little name
through a bunch of bureaucracy and i
lost that job i chose the name it was
kind of pungent to be honest so and even
at that time i had no interest in being
a chemist i do not enjoy the industries
i really really hate it
[Music]
you